<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-08T20:50:18-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lansing Tech Studio</title><subtitle>Empowering youth through technology, robotics, and community service. Supporting FIRST LEGO League teams, hosting coding bootcamps, and making a difference.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Lansing Tech Studio!</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/announcements/welcome/2025/01/15/welcome-to-lansing-tech-studio.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Lansing Tech Studio!" /><published>2025-01-15T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-15T10:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/announcements/welcome/2025/01/15/welcome-to-lansing-tech-studio</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/announcements/welcome/2025/01/15/welcome-to-lansing-tech-studio.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re thrilled to officially launch the new Lansing Tech Studio website! This has been a labor of love created by our student developers and mentors, and we couldn’t be more excited to share it with our community.</p>

<h2 id="what-makes-us-different">What Makes Us Different</h2>

<p>At Lansing Tech Studio, we believe that technology education should be:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Hands-on</strong>: Students learn by building, coding, and creating real projects</li>
  <li><strong>Collaborative</strong>: Teamwork and peer learning are at the heart of everything we do</li>
  <li><strong>Community-focused</strong>: We use our skills to make a positive impact in our local community</li>
  <li><strong>Inclusive</strong>: Everyone is welcome, regardless of experience level or background</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="current-season-update">Current Season Update</h2>

<p>Our FIRST LEGO League teams are deep into preparation for the upcoming regional tournament on January 25th. This year’s challenge, “SUBMERGED℠,” has pushed our students to think creatively about ocean exploration and conservation.</p>

<h3 id="team-highlights">Team Highlights:</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Robo Sharks</strong>: Working on an innovative coral reef restoration project</li>
  <li><strong>Deep Sea Coders</strong>: Developing underwater cleanup solutions</li>
  <li><strong>Ocean Explorers</strong>: Focusing on marine life protection initiatives</li>
</ul>

<p>Each team has been meeting every Saturday since September, and their dedication and creativity continue to amaze us.</p>

<h2 id="looking-ahead">Looking Ahead</h2>

<p>We have several exciting initiatives planned for 2025:</p>

<h3 id="spring-programs">Spring Programs</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Coding Bootcamp</strong>: 8-week intensive Python programming course (March-April)</li>
  <li><strong>Web Development Workshop</strong>: Build your first website (May)</li>
  <li><strong>Arduino Adventures</strong>: Hardware programming for beginners (June)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="summer-opportunities">Summer Opportunities</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>STEM Summer Camp</strong>: Week-long day camps for different age groups</li>
  <li><strong>Maker Projects</strong>: Advanced building and programming challenges</li>
  <li><strong>Community Service Intensive</strong>: Major community impact projects</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="new-partnerships">New Partnerships</h3>
<p>We’re excited to announce new partnerships with:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Capital Area District Libraries for coding workshops</li>
  <li>Lansing Community College for advanced mentoring</li>
  <li>Local engineering firms for career exploration</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="how-you-can-get-involved">How You Can Get Involved</h2>

<p>Whether you’re a student, parent, or community member, there are many ways to join our mission:</p>

<p><strong>For Students:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Register for upcoming workshops and camps</li>
  <li>Join a FIRST LEGO League team next season</li>
  <li>Participate in our community service projects</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>For Parents:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Volunteer as a mentor or coach</li>
  <li>Help with events and transportation</li>
  <li>Join our parent communication network</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>For Community Members:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Sponsor our programs and equipment</li>
  <li>Provide professional mentoring</li>
  <li>Offer internship opportunities</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>For Businesses:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Partner with us for student projects</li>
  <li>Sponsor teams and events</li>
  <li>Provide resources and expertise</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="success-stories">Success Stories</h2>

<p>We’re proud to share that several of our alumni have gone on to pursue STEM careers:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Lansing Tech Studio gave me the confidence to pursue computer science in college. The mentorship and hands-on learning prepared me for real-world challenges in ways that traditional classroom learning never could.” - Sarah M., University of Michigan Computer Science student</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Working on community service projects with my FLL team taught me that technology isn’t just about building cool things - it’s about solving real problems that matter to people.” - Marcus L., now studying engineering at MSU</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="thank-you-to-our-supporters">Thank You to Our Supporters</h2>

<p>None of this would be possible without our amazing sponsors and community partners:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Tech Innovations Inc.</strong> - Our platinum sponsor providing major funding and mentorship</li>
  <li><strong>Lansing Community Bank</strong> - Supporting our equipment purchases</li>
  <li><strong>Midwest Engineering Solutions</strong> - Offering professional development for our mentors</li>
  <li><strong>Local businesses</strong> - Providing supplies, services, and encouragement</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="join-our-community">Join Our Community</h2>

<p>Ready to be part of something amazing? Here’s how to stay connected:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Follow us on social media</strong> for daily updates and behind-the-scenes content</li>
  <li><strong>Subscribe to our newsletter</strong> for monthly program updates</li>
  <li><strong>Attend our events</strong> and see our students in action</li>
  <li><strong>Contact us</strong> to learn about volunteer and sponsorship opportunities</li>
</ul>

<p>We’re building more than robots and websites - we’re building the future leaders, innovators, and problem-solvers our community needs. Come join us on this incredible journey!</p>

<hr />

<p><em>Questions about our programs? Want to get involved? <a href="/contact">Contact us</a> - we’d love to hear from you!</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Brendon Thompson</name></author><category term="announcements" /><category term="welcome" /><category term="fll" /><category term="robotics" /><category term="community" /><category term="launch" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're excited to announce the official launch of Lansing Tech Studio's new website and share our vision for empowering youth through technology and community service.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Preparing for Regional Competition: Team Updates</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/competition/teams/2025/01/10/preparing-for-regionals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preparing for Regional Competition: Team Updates" /><published>2025-01-10T14:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-10T14:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/competition/teams/2025/01/10/preparing-for-regionals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/competition/teams/2025/01/10/preparing-for-regionals.html"><![CDATA[<p>The energy in our workshop has been electric these past few weeks! Our three FIRST LEGO League teams are in full preparation mode for the January 25th regional tournament, and we couldn’t be more proud of their dedication and creativity.</p>

<h2 id="team-progress-updates">Team Progress Updates</h2>

<h3 id="robo-sharks-">Robo Sharks 🦈</h3>
<p><strong>Focus</strong>: Coral Reef Restoration
<strong>Innovation Project</strong>: Smart Coral Monitoring System</p>

<p>The Robo Sharks have developed an incredible solution for monitoring coral reef health using underwater sensors and AI analysis. Their robot consistently scores 280+ points in practice runs, and their presentation skills have improved dramatically.</p>

<p><strong>Recent Achievements:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Completed their innovation project prototype</li>
  <li>Mastered 8 out of 10 robot missions</li>
  <li>Presented to local marine biology experts for feedback</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Quote from Team Captain Emma (age 14):</strong> “Learning about coral bleaching made us realize how important our oceans are. Our monitoring system could help marine biologists track reef health in real-time and respond faster to threats.”</p>

<h3 id="deep-sea-coders-">Deep Sea Coders 💻</h3>
<p><strong>Focus</strong>: Ocean Plastic Cleanup
<strong>Innovation Project</strong>: Autonomous Cleanup Drone Network</p>

<p>This team has blown us away with their ambitious project to create a network of autonomous drones that can identify and collect plastic waste from ocean surfaces. Their programming skills have grown exponentially this season.</p>

<p><strong>Recent Achievements:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Built a working prototype of their cleanup drone</li>
  <li>Scored 295 points in their best robot run</li>
  <li>Partnered with a local environmental group for project validation</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Quote from Team Member Alex (age 13):</strong> “We started this season barely knowing how to program a motor. Now we’re building autonomous systems! It shows what you can accomplish when you work together and don’t give up.”</p>

<h3 id="ocean-explorers-">Ocean Explorers 🌊</h3>
<p><strong>Focus</strong>: Marine Life Protection
<strong>Innovation Project</strong>: Smart Fishing Net Technology</p>

<p>The Ocean Explorers have tackled the problem of bycatch in commercial fishing with their smart net design that can selectively release non-target species. Their solution combines engineering creativity with environmental awareness.</p>

<p><strong>Recent Achievements:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Created detailed technical drawings and 3D models</li>
  <li>Consulted with local fishermen and marine biologists</li>
  <li>Developed a comprehensive implementation plan</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Quote from Team Member Jordan (age 12):</strong> “We learned that sometimes the best solutions are simple ones. Our net design doesn’t require expensive technology, but it could save thousands of sea turtles and dolphins.”</p>

<h2 id="competition-day-logistics">Competition Day Logistics</h2>

<h3 id="tournament-details">Tournament Details</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Date</strong>: Saturday, January 25, 2025</li>
  <li><strong>Location</strong>: Michigan State University Engineering Building</li>
  <li><strong>Schedule</strong>: 7:00 AM departure, 8:00 PM return (estimated)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-to-expect">What to Expect</h3>
<p>The regional tournament includes four main components:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Robot Performance</strong> (3 rounds, 2.5 minutes each)</li>
  <li><strong>Innovation Project Presentation</strong> (5 minutes + Q&amp;A)</li>
  <li><strong>Core Values Activities</strong> (Teamwork challenges)</li>
  <li><strong>Robot Design Interview</strong> (Technical discussion)</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="parent-information">Parent Information</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Transportation will be provided via chartered bus</li>
  <li>Teams will eat lunch at the venue (provided)</li>
  <li>Awards ceremony begins at approximately 4:00 PM</li>
  <li>Please arrive at pickup location by 6:45 AM</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="behind-the-scenes-what-makes-success">Behind the Scenes: What Makes Success</h2>

<h3 id="mentor-spotlight">Mentor Spotlight</h3>
<p>Our volunteer mentors have been incredible this season:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Dr. Lisa Chen</strong> (Software Engineer): “Watching these kids debug code and iterate on designs teaches me new ways to approach problems in my own work.”</li>
  <li><strong>Mike Rodriguez</strong> (Mechanical Engineer): “Their creativity is unlimited. They come up with solutions I never would have thought of.”</li>
  <li><strong>Jessica Park</strong> (High School CS Teacher): “The growth in their confidence and technical skills over just a few months is remarkable.”</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="student-leadership">Student Leadership</h3>
<p>We’re particularly proud of how our older students have stepped up as peer mentors:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Teaching younger teammates programming concepts</li>
  <li>Leading design review sessions</li>
  <li>Organizing practice schedules</li>
  <li>Providing emotional support during challenging moments</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="competition-strategy">Competition Strategy</h2>

<h3 id="final-preparation-checklist">Final Preparation Checklist</h3>
<p>✅ Robot programming completed and tested<br />
✅ Innovation project presentation rehearsed<br />
✅ Team uniforms and pit setup materials ready<br />
✅ Core values activities practiced<br />
✅ Backup plans for technical difficulties prepared</p>

<h3 id="goals-for-competition-day">Goals for Competition Day</h3>
<p>While we’d love to advance to the state championship, our primary goals are:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Have fun and represent our values</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Learn from other teams and judges</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Celebrate the journey and growth</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Inspire other young people</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Come home excited for next season</strong></li>
</ol>

<h2 id="community-support">Community Support</h2>

<p>The support from our community has been overwhelming:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>50+ family members</strong> planning to attend as spectators</li>
  <li><strong>Local businesses</strong> providing healthy snacks for the bus ride</li>
  <li><strong>High school alumni</strong> sending encouraging messages</li>
  <li><strong>Sponsor representatives</strong> planning to visit our pit area</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="special-thanks">Special Thanks</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Tech Innovations Inc.</strong> for funding our registration fees</li>
  <li><strong>Lansing Community Bank</strong> for supporting transportation costs</li>
  <li><strong>Tony’s Pizza</strong> for providing team dinner during final prep week</li>
  <li><strong>All the families</strong> who have volunteered countless hours</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="looking-beyond-competition">Looking Beyond Competition</h2>

<p>Regardless of Saturday’s results, we’re already planning for next season:</p>

<h3 id="post-competition-activities">Post-Competition Activities</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>February</strong>: Reflection sessions and season wrap-up</li>
  <li><strong>March</strong>: Recruitment for new teams</li>
  <li><strong>April</strong>: Spring Festival and community demonstration</li>
  <li><strong>May</strong>: Annual hack-a-thon fundraiser</li>
  <li><strong>Summer</strong>: Optional camps and advanced workshops</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="skills-for-life">Skills for Life</h3>
<p>The technical skills are just the beginning. Through FIRST LEGO League, our students develop:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Problem-solving abilities</strong> that transfer to any field</li>
  <li><strong>Communication skills</strong> through presentations and teamwork</li>
  <li><strong>Resilience</strong> by learning from failures and setbacks</li>
  <li><strong>Leadership</strong> by taking ownership of projects</li>
  <li><strong>Empathy</strong> through community-focused innovation projects</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="follow-our-journey">Follow Our Journey</h2>

<p>Want to cheer on our teams at regionals? Here’s how to stay connected:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Live Updates</strong>: Follow our Facebook page for real-time posts from competition</li>
  <li><strong>Photo Gallery</strong>: Check our website for pictures throughout the day</li>
  <li><strong>Video Highlights</strong>: Subscribe to our YouTube channel for post-competition interviews</li>
  <li><strong>Celebration Event</strong>: Join us Sunday, January 26 at 2:00 PM for a team celebration (location TBA)</li>
</ul>

<p>No matter what happens on Saturday, we’re already winners. These students have worked hard, supported each other, and created solutions that could genuinely make our world better. That’s what FIRST is all about.</p>

<p><strong>Go teams! 🤖🏆</strong></p>

<hr />

<p><em>Want to support our teams? <a href="/sponsors">Consider becoming a sponsor</a> or <a href="/contact#volunteer">volunteer with us</a> for next season!</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Coach Sarah</name></author><category term="competition" /><category term="teams" /><category term="fll" /><category term="regionals" /><category term="robots" /><category term="innovation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With less than two weeks until our regional tournament, our FLL teams are putting the finishing touches on their robots and innovation projects. Here's what they've been working on.]]></summary></entry></feed>